Brooklyn Rediscovery Folklife Study Project collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 4: Brooklyn community traditions, 1980-1983
  - Store fronts; Ukrainian Christmas, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 9/14)
    Photographs mostly or all by Sheldon Posen. Mixed content, including Jewish, Ukrainian, Bay Ridge Fish Market, as well as walls and murals.
  - Brooklyn Posters, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 11/24)
  - "Ritual Journeys" signs, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 20/50)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Signs about communities in Brooklyn.
  - "Making Brooklyn Home" signs, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 20/51)
  - Unidentified content, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 9/15)
  - Christmas traditions, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 10/22-11/22)
  - Christmas traditions, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 21/58)
  - "Manteo Ancona"; marionettes from Manteo Family Sicilian Marionette Theater 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 13/37)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper. From original slide: "Papa Manteo's Marionettes." Photographs of elaborate puppets/figurines.
  - "Manteo," 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 21/54)
    Manteo Family Sicilian Marionette Theater. Photographs by Martha Cooper. Marionettes.
  - Mixed content, 1980-1981, 35mm color slides (Box-group 13/39-14/39)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper. Mixed content, including documentation of Irish, Chinese, West Indian, and Italian communities.
- Series 5: Folklife Study related materials, 1980-1983
  Manuscripts, including field notes, papers, calendars, clippings, and administrative forms, relating to the Brooklyn Rediscovery Folklife Study Project.
  - Conversations, 1981-1982, manuscripts (Box-folder 3/1)
    Notes from conversations with folklorists, subject specialists, and librarians about the Brooklyn Rediscovery Folklife Study Project collection, potential communities to study, and potential fieldworkers, informants, and other contacts.
  - Field notebooks, 1981-1983, manuscripts (Box-folder 3/2)
    3 small field notebooks with notes, observations, recipes, event listings, traditions, and contact names and organizations.
  - Clippings, 1980-1983, manuscripts (Box-folder 3/3)
    Newspaper clippings and program booklets about Brooklyn's immigrant communities, neighborhoods, and traditions and practices.
  - Brooklyn calendar, 1980-1983, manuscripts; 1 black-and-white photographic print (Box-folder 3/4)
    Lists of upcoming Brooklyn festivals and celebrations to investigate, including specific locations. One black-and-white photographic print of "old Brooklyn" (Myrtle St.), undated.
  - Staub regionality/Brooklyn, 1980-1981, manuscripts (Box-folder 3/5)
    Shalom Staub paper "Toward a Theory of Regionality: the Case of the Urban Region, Brooklyn, USA" and correspondence from Staub.
  - Brooks MacNamara paper, May 1982, manuscripts (Box-folder 3/6)
    Brooks MacNamara presentation (including slide numbers) about traditional folk performances and theater.
  - Archives: accessioning forms, 1980-1981, manuscripts (Box-folder 3/7)
    Includes Sheldon Posen and Ricki Rosen's photo logs, correspondence with Neil Rosenberg, examples of documentation from American Folklife Center Field Survey Projects, and article about how to file and store photographic slides.
  - Sound recording documentation, February, 1982, manuscripts (Box-folder 3/8)
    Includes notes that correspond with SR001.
  - Black-and-white negatives, 984 black-and-white negatives (35mm) (Box 4)
  - Color negatives, 61 color negatives (35mm) (Box 5)